

Sergiy M. Ponomarenko

Python Developer

- **12.12.1978**
- Kyiv, Ukraine
- +380 93 563 29 53
- sergiy.ponomarenko@gmail.com
- https://sergiokapone.github.io

Social Network —

- in LinkedIn
- Github

Languages

- English (Intermediate) • •
- Ukrainian (Native)

Tech Skills -

- Python
- Django
- 🕏 FastAPI
- SQL / SQLAlchemy
- MongoDB
- JavaScript / 🗐 Node.JS
- ATEX

Soft Skills

- Punctuality
- Result orientation
- Attentive to details
- (A) Stress Tollerance

About Me

I am a physicist with a doctoral degree in physics of polymers. I have teaching experience and a passion for programming.

My research and teaching background has allowed me to utilize programming, especially Python, for automating routine tasks, analyzing and processing complex data, visualizing physical phenomena, and modeling physical processes.

I always strive to improve my skills and explore new technologies. I enjoy working in the areas of data analysis, modeling of physical systems and processes, and software development for scientific and engineering tasks.

Working Experience

2013 - currently

Company: Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute, Department of Applied Physics

Position: Associate Professor of Applied Physics

Responsibilities:

- Teaching: Developing and conducting lectures, seminars and practical classes in various courses of applied physics.
- Research activity: Conducting scientific research in the field of applied physics. Publication of research results in scientific journals. Participation in conferences and symposia.
- Student supervision: Guide and support students in research projects and laboratory work. Advising on research-related issues.
- Learning Materials: Create and organize learning materials, including assignments, tests, and evaluation criteria.
- Participation in administrative work: Performing administrative duties of the Deputy Dean for International Activities, Academic Secretary of the Department.
- Advising: Provide counseling to students on matters related to applied physics courses, their research and projects.
- Professional development: Continuous professional development, study of new teaching methods and scientific approaches in the field of applied physics.

2005 - 2013 Company: Kyiv National University of Construction and Architecture, Department of Physics

Position: Assistant/Associate Professor of Physics.

Education

Developer

2023 **Python Developer** GoIT Global Graduated the Python Core and Python Web course.

Physicist

2001 – 2005 **PhD in Physicsof Polymers** IMS NAS of Ukraine Defend PhD Thesis in Polymer Physisc.

1995 – 2001 **Masters Degree in Physics** Mykolaiv State Univercity Graduated from uni and majored in physics.